Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
A Concentrated Course in Traditional Harmony (text) 1942-43 9/227
...Traditional Harmony, part 2 (text) 1949 43,9/238
Tränen krüglein (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Trauermusik (va/vn/vc & string orchestra) 1936 3/125
Traumwald, opus 13, 4 songs (S & string quartet) 1917-19 1/22
Triadic Ballet, opus 40 (player-org) 1926 2/67
Trink aus! (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Trio (heckelphone, va, pf), opus 47 1928 2/89
Two small trios (fl, cl, cb) 1927 2/80
Triosatz (3 guitars) 1930 2/100
Trooper's Drinking Song (SSATB unaccompanied) 1937 3/132
True Love (SSATB unaccompanied) 1938 3/132
Trübes Wetter (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Tuttifäntchen - Christmas stories 1922 1/46
Two Pieces (organ) 1918 1/14
U Year Box/Folder
Über das Frühjahr (male chorus unaccompanied) 1929 2/94
Übung in drei Stücken (pf), opus 37 1. 1925 2/62
Übungen für Geiger - 5 etudes (solo vn) 1926 2/68
Übungstücke (strings, brass, winds) 1932 3/109
Das Unaufhörliche (oratorio) 1931 2/104
Unterhaltungsmusik (2 cl) 1934 3/117
V Year Box/Folder
Variationen über ein...Tanzlied (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/152
Das verfluchte Geld (male chorus unaccompanied) 1939 4/146
Vidit Joannes Jesum (S/T & pf) 1959 5/162
Vier Lieder (Busch) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (M. Claudius) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (Novalis) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (Rückert) 1933 3/115
Vier Lieder (Silesius) 1935 3/124
Vierzehn leichte Stücke in 1st position (2 vn) 1931 2/105
Vision des Mannes (male chorus unaccompanied) 1930 2/99
Das Vorspiel zum "Tristan" (text) 1965? 10/245
W Year Box/Folder
Seven Waltzes, opus 6 (pf, 4-hands) 1916 1/8
Wer wusste je (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
When lilacs last in the dooryard bloom'd (requiem) 1946 6/185
The Whistlin' Thief (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Wie es wär... (S, fl, ob, hn, string quartet) 1918 1/14
The Wild Flower's Song (S & pf) 1942-44 5/171
Wir bauen eine Stadt (musical play for children) 1930 2/96
Z Year Box/Folder
Zum Abshiede meiner Tochter (S & pf) 1942-43 5/172
Zwei Balladen (voice & pf) 1942 5/168,181
Zwei Lieder (Brentano) (voice & pf) 1936 3/130
Zwei Lieder (Cox) (S & pf) 1955 7/209
Zwölf Madrigale (SSATB unaccompanied) 1958 8/215
Collegium musicum (Yale University); Composers -- Germany -- 20th Century; Composers -- United States -- 20th Century; Music -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- 20th Century; Boatwright, Howard, 1918-1999; Cox, Oscar; Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970; Feist, Leonard, 1910-1996; French, Richard F. (Richard Frederic), 1915-2001; Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954; Goodman, Benny, 1909-1986; Hindemith, Gertrud, 1900-1967; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Miller, Carl S., 1917-2001; Noss, Luther, 1907-1995; Noss, Osea; O'Meara, Eva Judd; Schonthal, Ruth, 1924-2006; Simonds, Bruce; Simonds, Rosalind Brown; Wilder, Isabel, 1900-1995; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Associated Music Publishers; Yale School of Music
- MATERIAL RELATING TO HINDEMITH'S COMPOSITIONS, 1913-1993; Series I; 3.5' (8 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I presents the sequence of materials relating to Paul Hindemith's compositions as they were collected by Luther Noss. Arranged roughly in chronological order, each composition is assigned one or more folders which contain documents, reviews, articles, and commentaries. With a few exceptions, there are no published scores in the Collection; these are contained in the reference and circulating collections of the Yale University Music Library. In addition, works by other composers which were edited for publication or arranged by Hindemith appear in the chronology.
  The Box numbers and Folder numbers are consecutive throughout the Collection. Oversized items are housed in Box 43. The holographs, slightly larger than average, are contained in Boxes 31-32.
  Cross references are made where a photocopy or holograph could not be fitted into the consecutive numbering of Boxes or Folders because of its size.
  Programs and reviews of performances are filed under the title of the composition.
  Beginning with Folder 118, most letters listed under composition title are excerpts, complete texts of which may be found among the Correspondence in Boxes 15-17 and Boxes 21-23.
  - Hoch Conservatory, Frankfurt + Richard Strauss program (1912), 1913-14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Andante and Scherzo for clarinet, horn, piano, opus 1, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - String Quartet in C, opus 2, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Concerto in E-flat for violoncello and orchestra, opus 3, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - W. Kirsch: foreword III, 5
    - Lecture by L. Finscher at Philipps University, Marburg
  - Lustige Sinfonietta, opus 1, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Songs in the Aargau Dialect, opus 5, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - March in f minor for piano, four-hands, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Seven Waltzes for piano, four-hands, opus 6, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Piano Quintet in e minor, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letter of instructions to Emma Lübbecke-Job
    - Review Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung 1963, 1970
  - Three Pieces for violoncello and piano, opus 8, Paul Hindemith's first published work [Breitkopf & Härtel], 1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - P. Cahn: foreword V, 6
  - Three Songs for soprano and orchestra, opus 9, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - String Quartet in f minor, opus 10, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - W. Pütz: analysis from his monograph on the string quartets
  - Sonata for Ten Instruments (opus 10a), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wie es wär, wenn's anders wär, for soprano, flute, oboe, horn, 2 violins, viola, violoncello Two Pieces for organ, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sonata in B-flat for violin and piano, opus 11 no. 1 (originally opus 11 no. 2), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - J. Lyons: record notes
    - Excerpts from P. Cahn: foreword in V, 6 for above, for all string sonatas, for opus 11 sonatas
  - Sonata in D for violin and piano, opus 11 no. 2 (originally opus 11 no. 3), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - P. Cahn: foreword V, 6
  - Sonata for violoncello and piano, opus 11 no. 3 (originally opus 11 no. 6), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - P. Cahn: foreword V, 6
    - Program 1975 Laurie Laufman
  - Sonata for viola and piano, opus 11 no. 4, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - P. Cahn: foreword V, 6
    - Programs: 1972, 1974, 1976
    - D. Reinker: student paper
  - Sonata for solo viola, opus 11 no. 5, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sonata in c minor for solo violin, opus 11 no. 6, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mörder, Hoffnung der Frauen, opus 12 - one-act opera, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Kokoschka obituary 1980
    - L. Finscher: foreword I, 5
    - K. V. Maur: "Oskar Schlemmer and Paul Hindemith," Jahrbuch IV/74
    - Libretto in rough translation
    - Review: Neue Zeitschrift für Musik, 1970
  - Traumwald, opus 13 - four songs for soprano and string quartet; text: Christian Morgenstern, 1917-19 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Three Hymns, opus 14 for baritone and piano, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - No. 3 is initial version of Sing on there in the swamp (see "When lilacs last in the dooryard bloom'd," also holograph Box 31, File 430)
  - In einer Nacht, opus 15 - [14 short pieces] for piano, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - [Second] String Quartet in C, opus 16, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - D. Rexroth: analysis in Jahrbuch II/72 - longhand translation
    - W. Pütz: analysis from his monograph on the String Quartets
    - D. Rexroth: notes for recordings (opus 16 & 22)
    - A. Weismann: article in Die Musik 1924 - longhand translation
    - Programs: 1972, 1981
  - Sonata for piano, opus 17, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Acht Lieder, opus 18 for soprano and piano, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Facsimile of No. 6 Du machst mich...
    - Text translations
    - Program 1986
  - [Five] Dance Pieces for piano, opus 19, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Das Nusch-Nuschi, opus 20, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Notes: P. Epstein 1931, London Observer 1955, I. Kemp 1970
    - Libretto in rough translation
    - L. Finscher: foreword I, 5
  - Das Nusch-Nuschi, orchestral suite, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Sancta Susanna, opus 21 - one-act opera, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Reviews & notes: 1922, 1931, 1951, 1970
    - L. Finscher: foreword I, 5
    - Libretto in rough translation
    - K. von Mauer: "Oskar Schlemmer and Paul Hindemith," Jahrbuch IV/74
    - Notes & reviews: 1962, 1965, 1978, 1984
    - Music Library Association Notes review
  - [Third] String Quartet, opus 22, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Notes by D. Rexroth from 1976 recording
    - Programs: 1973, 1976, 1984
    - Original program from 14 April 1923 by Amar Quartet
    - W. Pütz: analysis from monograph
  - Five Pieces for Piano; The Atonal Cabaret, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Des Todes Tod, opus 23a - three poems by E. Reinacker for female voice, 2 violins, 2 violoncelli, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Rough translation of poems
  - Die junge Magd, opus 23b for contralto, flute, clarinet, 2 violins, viola, violoncello, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Rough translation of text
    - Progam 1961; notes from 1981 & 1984 performances
  - Kanunermusik No. 1, opus 24 no. 1, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Notes from Paul Hindemith journal 1938, I. Kemp, C. Searchinger, H. Strobel
    - D. de la Mottee: article in Jahrbuch IV/77
    - Melos article 1928 & 1958
    - Yale programs & reviews: 1973, 1979, 1981, 1986
  - Kleine Kammermusik, opus 24 no. 2 for woodwind quintet, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Reviews: 1939 + Paul Hindemith comments, 1946, 1967, 1981, 1982, 1989
  - Sonata for solo viola, opus 25 no. 1, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - P. Cahn: foreword from V, 6
    - O. Downes: review of Coolidge Festival 1937
    - Paul Ehrlich: student paper
    - A. Greither: "Paul Hindemith and Ladislav Cerny," Jahrbuch VIII/79
    - Program 1987
  - Sonata for viola d'amore and piano, opus 25 no. 2, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    General
    (see also Box 9, Folder 238-lecture: On the viola d'amore. Cremona 1937)
    - P. Cahn: foreword from V, 6
    - Program notes 1981
  - Sonata for solo violoncello, opus 25 no. 3, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Notes & correspondence re: Laurel Rogers masters thesis
    - D. Tabbet: student paper
  - Sonata for viola and piano, opus 25 no. 4, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - P. Cahn: foreword to V, 6
    - Notes from lst performance in Blonay 1976
    - Review 1980
    - Notice 1981
    - Program 1981
  - Piano Suite "1922" (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - F. Göbels: notes for Bärenreiter recording
    - B. Billeter: notes for Musical Heritage Society recording
    - F. Göbels: "From the Suite 1922 to Ludus Tonalis," Jahrbuch II/72
    - Program 1973
  - Das Marienleben, opus 27 - 15 poems by Rainer Maria Rilke, 1922-23 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Notes: H. Strobel biography, 2nd ed. 1931
    - Notes: Skelton biography
    - Notes: L. Morton for GSC recording
    - Program 1975
  - Der Dämon, opus 28 - dance pantomime/ballet, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    (see also Box 8, Folder 220 - Juilliard performance 1963)
    - Synopsis
    - Notes: H. Schramm from Candide recording
    - Notes: Scarlatti Orchestra of Naples recording by H. Sheridan 1952
    - Notes: A. Schwartz from University of Illinois broadcast 1980
  - Der Dämon, orchestral suite, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Program 1981
  - Tuttifäntchen - Christmas stories in three scenes, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Piano Concerto for the Left Hand, opus 29, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Notes & correspondence re: Paul Wittgenstein who commissioned it
  - Quintet for clarinet and string quartet, opus 30, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Notes by H. Halbreich for Musical Heritage Society recording
    - Program 1981
  - Sonata for solo violin, opus 31 no. 1, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Sonata for solo violin, opus 31 no. 2, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - H. Shiller: student paper
    - Program 1990
  - Canonic Sonatina for two flutes, opus 31 no. 3, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Program 1973
  - Sonata for solo viola, opus 31 no. 4, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Photocopy of manuscript by H. Burkhart
  - [Fourth] String Quartet, opus 32, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Review from The London Times in New York Times 13/l/29
    - Photocopy of fugue theme from Ist movement + fugue theme from First String Trio, 4th movement
    - W. Püsz: analysis from monograph
  - Minimax, Repertorium für Militärmusik for string quartet, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - E. R. Jacobi: article in Jahrbuch III/73
    - Copy of printed score: Schott, 1978
  - Sechs Lieder nach alten Texten for mixed chorus unaccompanied, 1923-24 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Notes from A. Rubeli's book. Frankfurt 1975
  - (First) String Trio, opus 34, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Notes from recordings: Musical Heritage Society, Westminster, et. al.
  - Die Serenaden, opus 35, for soprano, oboe, viola, violoncello, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Notes by R. Evett from GSC recording
    - Review: 22 May 1927 New York Times translated from Paris Revue Musicale
    - Photocopy of Gertrud's name in 1920-25 sketchbooks
    - Translations of vocal texts; programs 1961-1972
  - Kammermusik No. 2, opus 36 no. 1 [with piano solo], 1924 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - R. McMahan: notes for Louisville Orchestra recording
    - S. Svercek paper: A study... [of] Kammermusik no. 2 and Quartet (1938)
    - Programs: Eugene, Oregon festival 1981, B. Berman 1986
    - Reviews of Balanchine's "Kammermusik" ballet: 1978, 1980, 1981
  - Kammermusik No. 3, opus 36 no. 2 [with violoncello solo], 1925 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Notes by J. Braunstein ca. 1965
    - Review: New Haven Register 1979
    - Program 1978
  - Kammermusik No. 4, opus 36 no. 3 [with violin solo], 1925 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - L. Biancolli: review from New York World Telegram 1946?
    - E. Stein: student paper 1974
  - Kammermusik No. 5, opus 36 no. 4 [with viola solo], 1927 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Notes from Paul Hindemith journal after Boston rehearsal 1938, from Yale 1984 performance
  - Klaviermusik, opus 37 I: Übung in drei Stücken, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Klaviermusik, opus 37 II: Reihe [12] kleiner Stücke, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - H. Kleeman monograph: Hindemith's Composition Principle and its Relation to Atonality 1928
  - Concerto for Orchestra, opus 38, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Review of premiere in Vienna 1927
    - Notes: I. Kemp: biography
    - Notes: A. Cohn: notes for Decca
    - H. Haack: analysis of final movement Jahrbuch I/75
  - Three Pieces for five instruments (Anecdotes for Radio) for piano, clarinet, trumpet, violin, bass, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Cardillac, opus 39 - opera in three acts, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Notes by G. Hauswald for DGG recording
    - Synopsis by L. Noss
    - Notes by G. Skelton, I. Kemp, A. Briner, W. Abendrot
    - Programs/announcements: Santa Fe 1967, Mainz 1968, Düsseldorf
    - Review: E. Helm 1961
    - I. Kolodin-R. Jacobson article in Saturday Review 1970
    - Reviews of Dresden premiere: W. Petzet in Signale 1926; P. Stefan in Musikblätter des Anbruch; E. Schmitz in Die Musik 1927 + photocopy
    - Replies to Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung questionnaire 1928: comments by K. Holla, E. Kleiber, O. Klemperer, Henry 45th Crown Prince Reuss, A. Weissmann, F. Wolfes, L. Wallerstein, J. Rosenstock
    - 1977 Berlin Festival Articles by D. Rexroth; Dr. I. Krengel-Strudhoff's article: The Remarkable Story of "The Maiden from Scuderi;" copy of Berlin Festival program
    - Review by H. Stuckenschmidt in Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung in Jahrbuch VI/77
  - Music for Mechanical Instruments, opus 40 1?. Toccata for player-piano 2?. Triadic Ballet, scored for player-organ, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Übungen für Geiger, [five etudes] for violin unaccompanied, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Konzertmusik für Blasorchester, opus 41, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Yale programs: 1971, 1976
  - A Collection of Freshly-laid Piano Eggs, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Sketches for opus 37 II, identified by Prof. Billeter April 1983
    - Photocopy of manuscript in Osborn Collection, Beineke Library
  - Spielmusik, opus 43 I für Streicher, Flöten und Oboen, 1926-27 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Spielmusik, opus 43 II - [Four] Lieder für Singkreise
  - Lieder für Singkreise, opus 43 II, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - A. Rubeli: article from Hindemiths a cappella Werke, 1975 Mainz
  - Schulwerk für Instrumental-zusammenspiel, opus 44 no. 1 - Nine Pieces for violins I-II, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Schulwerk für Instrumental-zusammenspiel, opus 44 no. 2 - Eight Pieces for violins I-II, viola(s), 1927 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Schulwerk für Instrumental-zusammenspiel, opus 44 no. 3 - Eight Pieces for Strings: violins I-II, viola, violoncello, double bass, as quintet or ensemble, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Schulwerk für Instrumental-zusammenspiel, opus 44 no. 4 - Five Pieces for String orchestra in first position, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Program 1978
  - Film Music: Felix the Cat (1927) for player-piano with newspaper clipping Vormittagsspuk (1928) for player-piano, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Acht Stücke für Flöte allein, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Programs: 1968, 1972
  - Nine Pieces for clarinet and double bass, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Two Small Trios for flute, clarinet, double bass, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Hin und Zurück, opus 45a - comic sketch/one-act opera, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Letter excerpts: W. Strecker 1939, Gertrud Hindemith 1940
    - Notes from Candide recording by H. Schranun
    - Translation of libretto
    - Programs: 1927, 1973
  - Sing- und Spielmusiken für Liebhaber und Musikfreunde, opus 45 for mezzo-soprano, baritone, 1-part and 2-part mixed chorus, string orchestra with wind instruments ad lib and audience participation, on text of Martin Luther 1. Frau Musica, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    (see also revised version Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Foreword by Paul Hindemith
    - Translation of Rubeli: article from The a caprella Works of Paul Hindemith
  - 2. Eight Canons for 2-part mixed chorus with violins I-II, viola, violoncello, ad lib, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    (see Rubeli: article Box 2, Folder 72)
  - 3. Ein Jäger aus Kurpfalz for strings and winds, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - 4. Kleine Klaviermusik - five pieces for piano, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - 5. Martinslied for solo voice/unison, three instrumental parts, audience participation, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Kammermusik No. 6, opus 46 no. 1 [with viola d'amore solo], 1927 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Kammermusik No. 7, opus 46 no. 2 [with organ solo], 1927 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Program: 1976 at Yale
  - Trio for heckelphone, viola, piano, opus 47 - Tenor saxophone may be substituted for heckelphone, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - R. Evett: notes for GSC recording
    - Programs: 1976, 1978
  - Neues vom Tage, comic opera in three acts, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Comments by G. Skelton, I. Kemp, H. Strobel, A. Briner
    - Reviews: 1929 by W. Hirschberg in Signale in Zeugnis
    - Translation of A. Einstein: German review in New York Times 1929
    - Translation of P. Epstein: article in Die Musik 1929
  - Lehrstück for tenor, 2 baritones, narrator, 3 speaking clowns, chorus, dancers, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Comments by G. Skelton, I. Kemp, H. Eisler 1957, unknown sources, M. Rieple
    - Rough translation of text
    - F. Hommel: An Experiment in Retrospect: Paul Hindemith and Berthold Brecht, Jahrbuch VI/77
    - Review: New York Times 1973
  - Sehr ruhig, photocopy of piano piece written for Josefa Grossova, Czech pianist, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Lindberghflug, 4 pieces for baritone solo, bass solo, alto solo, final chorus, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - 1. Über das Frühjahr, text by B. Brecht 2. Eine lichte Mitternacht, text by W. Whitman, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    for male chorus unaccompanied. (see Rubeli: article in Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Konzertmusik, opus 48 for Solo-Bratsche und grösseres Kammerorchester, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - R. McMahan: notes for Louisville recording
  - Wir bauen eine Stadt, musical play for children; two-part chorus with simple solo parts, optional orchestra of three parts: high, middle, low, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Rough translation in manuscript
    - Program 1988
  - Sabinchen, Hörspiel/radio play for two speakers?, solo quartet, chorus, orchestra, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Four [actually Seven] Pieces for three trautoniums, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Photocopy of score
    - Extract from K. Ebbeke: article in Jahrbuch 82/XI
  - 1. Du musst dir alles geben 2. Fürst Kraft 3. Vision des Mannes, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    for male chorus unaccompanied.
  - Triosatz/Rondo for three guitars, written as part of cantata Wanderlieder, to which other composers contributed, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Program 1981
  - Chorlieder für Knaben: 1. Bastellied 2. Lied des Musterknaben 3. Angst vorm Schwimmunterricht 4. Schundromane lesen, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Konzertmusik für Klavier, Blechbläser und zwei Harfen, opus 49, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Correspondence with E. S. Coolidge who commissioned it
    - A. Cohn: notes for Decca recording
    - Review: S. A. Lieberson in Die Musik 1931
    - Programs: 1975, Yale 1985 & 1993
  - Konzertmusik für Streichorchester und Blechbläser, opus 50 [so-called "Boston Symphony"], 1930 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Reviews from Baden 1950: G. Görgen in Musik im Unterricht; H. Hagen in Neue Zeitung; J. Lubbers in Die Welt; H. Reich in Badische Zeitung; K. Wagner in Musica
    - Note: Paul Hindemith journal 1938
    - Notes: 1938 Boston Symphony Orchestra performance
    - Notice: Grand Teton Festival 1978
    - Notes: Yale 1979 + program & review
    - Program Yale 1973
    - R. McMahan: student paper
  - Das Unaufhörliche, oratorio for mixed chorus, SATB soli, boys' choir, full symphony orchestra, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Comments by G. Skelton, I. Kemp
    - H. Peyser: review New York Times 1931
    - Correspondence re: Ohio State 1973 performance
    - D. Rexroth: comments from Paul Hindemith Briefe, 1982
    - L. Finscher review of A. Fehn: Gottfried Benn-Paul Hindemith correspondence in Der Ausschnitt 1979 + original in German; review of same by G. W. Baruch in Stuttgarter Zeitung 1979 + original in German
    - Reviews: Der Ausschnitt (Würzburg, Munich, Hannover 1979); Das historisch-politische Buch 1979; Wissenschaft Literatureinzeigen 1979; Das gute Buch 1979
    - text from Hessischer Rundfunk program 1979?
    - Rough translation of oratorio text
    - H. Connor: review of first publication 1932 in Die Musik
    - Translation of introduction to A. Fehn: article in Jahrbuch V/76
    - Notes from A. Fehn: monograph in Stanford University German Studies, Vol. 12
    - Article by W. M. in Berlin Festival program 1977
  - 1. Vierzehn leichte Stücke in first position for two violins 2. Fuge, in Doflein's Geigenschule, Vol. 6 for two violins 3. Drei Stücke/Etuden, in Vol. 7; referred to as Canonic Pieces/Studies, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Konzertstück für ein Trautonium mit Begleitung des Streichorchesters, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Photocopy of score
    - Letter from D. Rexroth to W. Ruff 1979
  - Philharmonisches Konzert, for 50th anniversary of Berlin Philharmonic, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Comments by I. Kemp, A. Briner
    - Program 1951
    - G. Sannemüller: article in Jahrbuch VI/77
    - H. Mautner: student paper
  - Plöner Musiktag, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - R. Evett: notes for Recorder Trio recording on GSC
    - Review by W. Konold of G. Sannemüller: monograph in Jahrbuch V/76
    - Photocopy of lecture by Paul Hindemith at Greenwich Settlement Music School, New York, 27 April 1937
    - Programs of excerpts: 1967, 1973, 1981
  - Übungsstücke für Streicher, Blechbläser, Holzbläser, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Der Tod for male chorus, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - String Trio II, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Comments from Westminster recording